<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Y. Jin</title>
 <link href="http://jyh1.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://jyh1.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2016-10-14T22:11:55+08:00</updated>
 <id>http://jyh1.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Jin Yonghao</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>About Me</title>
   <link href="http://jyh1.github.io/2016/10/01/introducing-myself/"/>
   <updated>2016-10-01T00:00:00+08:00</updated>
   <id>http://jyh1.github.io/2016/10/01/introducing-myself</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;My name is Yonghao Jin (靳永昊), a senior undergraduate from Department of Physics, &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.ustc.edu.cn/&quot;&gt;Universiy of Science and Technology of China(USTC)&lt;/a&gt;, majored in Applied Physics with concentration in Biophysics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;!-- ### Background --&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I have a diverse backgrounds in physics, computer science and biology. Having attended a complete undergraduate training in physics,
I acquired a strong quantitative foundation and I am able to use math as a tool to analyze and address complicate problems.
 I was first introduced to the world of computer science when I joined the informatics olympiad team in high school. Having spent nearly seven years in programming, I am adept in many programming contexts. In addition to completing the &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;National Olympiad Informatics in Province&lt;/code&gt; with the first prize, I also wrote programming language interpreters, pipelines for analyzing high throughput sequencing data, physics simulation programs, computer games and so on. My recent project is a &lt;code class=&quot;highlighter-rouge&quot;&gt;Mathematica&lt;/code&gt; language interpreter &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/jyh1/mmaclone&quot;&gt;mmaclone&lt;/a&gt;.
 Due to my concentration in biophysics, the required courses in biology covered many interesting topics in life sciences, molecular biology, theoretical neurology and biochemistry, just to name a few. These interesting courses provided me with sufficient knowledge and understanding in biological processes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I love the feeling of doing research. Currently, I am trying to integrate different sequencing-based probing data to understand the binding preference of RNA binding proteins (RBP) under the supervision of Prof. Kun Qu.
I feel that my backgrounds set me in a unique position to apply statistics, mathematics and computer science to deciphering and interpreting the big data in life sciences.
I am applying for Ph.D. programs in the fall of 2017.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
